<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Trinkets tech blog</title>
    <link>https://trinkets.tech/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Trinkets tech blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ShinyTrinkets/&#34;&gt;Shiny-Trinkets&lt;/a&gt; 2018-2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://trinkets.tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Software ecosystems: XXIIVV</title>
      <link>https://trinkets.tech/posts/19g12-software-ecosystems/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trinkets.tech/posts/19g12-software-ecosystems/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m fascinated every time I discover an ecosystem of apps and tools that is similar with what I&amp;rsquo;m trying to build here, with Trinkets. I feel excited like I&amp;rsquo;ve encountered an ancient civilization from another dimension, hidden for 1 million years.
It took me a week to study most of the interesting repositories when I could find some spare time. At first I was totally overwhelmed by the number of weird names (eg: Arvelie, Heol, Indental, Tablatal, Neralie, Oscean, Horaire) and I thought &amp;ldquo;Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s in Finnish, or maybe Volapük&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Interneț</title>
      <link>https://trinkets.tech/posts/19g11-hello-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trinkets.tech/posts/19g11-hello-again/</guid>
      <description>Hello again Interneț!
I just published this blog on the website https://trinkets.tech/ !
It is powered by the HUGO site generator.
The posts are still available in the https://github.com/ShinyTrinkets/docs/ repository and you can view the history of all changes.
I exploded the big &amp;ldquo;captain-log.md&amp;rdquo; file into separate files for each post. I intend to delete the captain-log after some time.
For the URL of the articles, for the months, I&amp;rsquo;m using letters instead of numbers, like so: A=january, B=february, &amp;hellip; K=november, L=december.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello, lack of internet</title>
      <link>https://trinkets.tech/posts/19g11-no-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trinkets.tech/posts/19g11-no-internet/</guid>
      <description>Hello, lack of internet&amp;hellip;
For some reason, I don&amp;rsquo;t have Internet today, so I can&amp;rsquo;t do much&amp;hellip;
However, it&amp;rsquo;s a blessing, because I realize just how much I depend on it.
Things that I have offline, so I was prepared:
 a ton of notes, TODOs, ideas, links to useful resources, saved as Markdown files some articles downloaded with ➹ Clean-mark all the posts for this website and all the history of the changes  Things what I wish I had (more of):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High level diagrams</title>
      <link>https://trinkets.tech/posts/19g03-diagram/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trinkets.tech/posts/19g03-diagram/</guid>
      <description>Procrastination and delay are both forms of lazyness. I&amp;rsquo;m fighting my own laziness daily. Sometimes I actually win&amp;hellip;
In one of my previous posts, I promised to publish some diagrams of the Trinkets architecture.
What I care about at the highest level is the data flow. Inputs and Outputs. All the implementation details are intentionally ignored, so Trinkets is just a &amp;ldquo;black box&amp;rdquo; that you can interact with.
A User can interact with Trinkets via command line, or via a browser user interface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ⓟ2Ⓟ Decentralized technologies</title>
      <link>https://trinkets.tech/posts/19g02-decentralized/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trinkets.tech/posts/19g02-decentralized/</guid>
      <description>I believe decentralized applications are very important and I&amp;rsquo;m not the only one to think that. I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching the P2P and crypto space for years. For me personally, decentralization technologies =equal= freedom. Freedom to choose where you send your data and where you store it. Because if there are no &amp;ldquo;cloud&amp;rdquo; servers, you are in control.
I want to use P2P network protocols for the Trinkets suite because there won&amp;rsquo;t be any servers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>️️Start of July 2019 updates</title>
      <link>https://trinkets.tech/posts/19g01-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trinkets.tech/posts/19g01-updates/</guid>
      <description>I believe the Overseer project is quite stable now, I put a lot of effort into making it better. I had to re-write a lot of the code, because when I started working at it, my Go-lang skills were horrible. I created a lot of tests, the coverage is ~94% now. Of course, that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean there are no bugs, but at least it&amp;rsquo;s a good measure of how well the tests are hitting the code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🧪 Elixir v1.9</title>
      <link>https://trinkets.tech/posts/19f27-elixir/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trinkets.tech/posts/19f27-elixir/</guid>
      <description>I was really really silent (publicly), for such a long time, wow&amp;hellip;
I was quite busy actually, on all the projects. More details will follow.
What I wanted to write today is: WOOOW, Elixir-lang implemented &amp;ldquo;build release&amp;rdquo; in their latest version !!
The official blog post: Elixir v1-9-0 released. TL;DR; from the article:
 Releases allow developers to precompile and package all of their code and the runtime into a single unit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🕸 New job at ScrapingHub</title>
      <link>https://trinkets.tech/posts/18k22-scrapinghub/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trinkets.tech/posts/18k22-scrapinghub/</guid>
      <description>I just started a new job at ScrapingHub and I&amp;rsquo;m really excited about it 😁
But at the same time, this means I&amp;rsquo;ll have to delay my work on these projects a little longer, until I get used to the new tools and projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>✂︎ TwoFold WIP 2</title>
      <link>https://trinkets.tech/posts/18j07-twofold/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trinkets.tech/posts/18j07-twofold/</guid>
      <description>Not too much progress with TwoFold (2✂︎f) these days&amp;hellip;
I discovered Nearley.js and I think it might solve my parsing dilemma.
Unfortunately, I have to work on some personal things these weeks, so I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ll make any progress this month 😢</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>✂︎ TwoFold WIP</title>
      <link>https://trinkets.tech/posts/18i27-twofold/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trinkets.tech/posts/18i27-twofold/</guid>
      <description>Wow man, where has this week gone ?! It&amp;rsquo;s already Thursday&amp;hellip;
I&amp;rsquo;m still working on TwoFold (2✂︎f) v0.2, because v0.1 is not that usable and friendly&amp;hellip;
I added the option to define you own tag start and end characters to create fancy tags like {{ whatever ? }}, or double tags like [[ whatever &amp;gt;]] ... [[&amp;lt; whatever ]].
I&amp;rsquo;m passing the parameters that could come from the tags, into the transformer functions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🚀 TwoFold v0.1</title>
      <link>https://trinkets.tech/posts/18i22-twofold/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trinkets.tech/posts/18i22-twofold/</guid>
      <description>I just launched TwoFold (2✂︎f) v0.1 on NPM !! 🎉
No. 1 reason I created TwoFold is &amp;hellip; to sort lines in my awesome lists 😂 And no. 2 is to fetch the Github or Gitlab status for those projects in the awesome lists. That&amp;rsquo;s what I want to do ASAP, but I want it done properly, so I&amp;rsquo;m taking the time.
I have huge hopes for this library, but there&amp;rsquo;s so much to do&amp;hellip; v0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>⭐️ ⚙️ The history of Trinkets</title>
      <link>https://trinkets.tech/posts/18i18-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trinkets.tech/posts/18i18-history/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s start with the beggining: what&amp;rsquo;s the focus of the Trinkets applications, when and where did this idea start and why this is still relevant today. I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about the &amp;ldquo;how&amp;rdquo; another time.
In 2008, I was working in a data processing company and I noticed that I was repeatedly doing the same things every X intervals of time. Depending on the client, some tasks were daily, others weekly, others monthly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Trinkets</title>
      <link>https://trinkets.tech/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trinkets.tech/about/</guid>
      <description>This blog is about the &amp;ldquo;Trinkets&amp;rdquo; project. You will find tech articles and general life philosophy around how to write code and manage projects. It is public in the hope that it is useful for somebody.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>⭐️ ⚙️ What is Trinkets</title>
      <link>https://trinkets.tech/posts/18h15-what-is-trinkets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trinkets.tech/posts/18h15-what-is-trinkets/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s time to explain the purpose of Trinkets and why it exists.
Some of the things are not yet crystal clear in my mind, so it might take some time to put them in writing and I might come back to edit this text in the future.
I&amp;rsquo;m using a Github repository and not a normal blog post, both because I&amp;rsquo;m lazy and because this is how I&amp;rsquo;ve worked for years, anyway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>☀️ 👋 Hello world</title>
      <link>https://trinkets.tech/posts/18g30-hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trinkets.tech/posts/18g30-hello-world/</guid>
      <description>This is my first ever public post regarding the Trinkets projects! Wheee ⭐️ 🎉 !!
I have to take the time to explain what is this thing about, and why I created it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://trinkets.tech/readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trinkets.tech/readme/</guid>
      <description>Trinkets 📖 blogs and specs 
Welcome to Shiny Trinkets documents!
This is work-in-progress. For now you can navigate to blogs/ and read the posts there.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>